# JASON (CHIAO CHUN) YANG

chiaojyang@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/jasonwithcoffee

Summary: First data scientist of a successful, profitable Series A startup, acquiring 2 companies over the last 2 years. Working with terabyte-scale data, I help marketers identify high impact strategies to connect with their customers.

# RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# InMarket Media | Data Scientist

Culver City, CA | 2018 – Present

- ❖ Expanded the data insights team from 2 to 5 to meet 9x growth in reporting capabilities, driving 108% increase in client retention and 317% increase in Share of Voice for major publications such as WSJ, CNBC.
- Developed and launched the InSights product across 100+ campaigns, generating \$1MM+ revenue annually.
- ❖ Introduced A/B testing and lift metrics to campaign reporting for evaluating performance.
- Conducts SWOT analysis, tests hypotheses, and produces reports and dashboards to executives and department leaders to recommend product direction and define standards.
- ❖ Developed time series decomposition analytics during COVID-19 to support digital lead generation.

# **OSIsoft** | *Product Support Engineer II*

San Francisco, CA | 2016 – 2018

- Designed, deployed, and maintained enterprise data warehousing solutions to Fortune 500 companies.
- Conducted linear regression on product support logs to forecast call volume for staffing and product growth.
- ♦ Devised technical solutions for hundreds of customers through calls and field services (CSAT Score: 5/5).

# **COMMUNITY VOLUNTEERING**

**FutureMap** | Data & Insights Manager

Los Angeles, CA | 2020 – Present

- \* Administers curriculum to help first-generation college graduates navigate their transition to the workforce.
- ❖ Develops with Google Drive API to handle engagement data from 200+ students, creating a data processing standard for evaluating impact and identifying actionable insights.

# **Hack for LA** | *Product Manager*

Santa Monica, CA | 2018 – Present

- \* Brings together civic-minded volunteers to build digital products to serve our local community.
- Founded the Job Match Project to better match job applicants to job openings using NLP and clustering.

### **RAWdance** | Board Member (Data Specialist)

San Francisco, CA | 2017 – 2018

- Conducted classification analyses to identify for donation KPIs using Python and Tableau.
- ❖ Managed the deployment of the central CRM database to ensure data integrity.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming**: Python (numpy, pandas, sklearn, xgboost, TensorFlow), SQL, Spark (Scala, PySpark)

Cloud: AWS (SageMaker, Redshift, EMR, EC2); Google Cloud (BigQuery, Dataproc, Cloud Functions)

Visualization: Tableau, Looker, Power BI, Data Studio

Certifications: AWS ML Specialty, SQL (Microsoft MTA 98-364)

#### **EDUCATION**

Stanford University 2020 - 2021

Graduate Courses: Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning

# **UC Berkeley** | *B.S. Chemical Engineering*

2011 - 2015

\* Research: Computational Fluid Dynamics